Guide to the Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts collection CBHM.0002
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 9: Local Eyes: Folk Photographers Documenting Brooklyn
  - Sub-series 9.1: Program Files
    - William DeMeritte, Oversize, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Mel Gerson, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Anders Goldfarb, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Irving Herzberg, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - John Huang, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - John Huang, Oversize, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Helen Marrero, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Cliff Matias, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Cliff Matias, Oversize, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Angie Picolo, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - Exhibit Brochure, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - Checklist and Wall Labels, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Exhibit Photographs, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Five Myles, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Research, Folk Photography, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Research, Prospect Park Archives, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 25)
- Series 10: Once Upon a Time in Brooklyn: Traditional Storytellers and Their Tales
  Once Upon a Time in Brooklyn: Traditional Storytellers and Their Tales was a series of eleven public programs and workshops produced by Kay Turner, Folk Arts Director at the Brooklyn Arts Council. The program ran from May-June 2011 and featured Brooklyn storytellers presenting folk tales, fairy tales, ghost stories, tall tales and the legends of saints in parks, libraries and community gardens around the borough.
  Program Files document expenses, funding, publicity, and research for the project. Research materials include press clippings, photocopies of articles, and book segments about stories and storytelling. This sub-series also includes biographical information about participants and signed permission statements for audio and video recordings. The Audiovisual sub-series includes digital photographs, audio, and video recordings of selected program events. See audiovisual sub-series for a full list.
  Once Upon a Time in Brooklyn events included:
  Festival Storytelling Session: Folk Tales from Guyana and Dominican Republic. Thomas Boyland Park, Ocean Hill-Brownsville, May 7, 2011.
  Enchanted Brooklyn: Contemporary Fairy Tale Films. BAMcinematek, May 9, 2011.
  Reading, Writing and Hearing Traditional Tales. Brooklyn Public Library, Bay Ridge, May 19, 2011.
  Lunchtime Story Swap. Elders Share the Arts, Fort Greene, May 23, 2011.
  Changing Skins: Folktales About Gender, Identity and Humanity. Dixon Place Theater, Manhattan, June 3, 2011.
  Garifuna Wonder Tales. BIKO, Bushwick, June 10, 2011.
  The Tower's Tale: Sacred Story and the Giglio Feast in Italian Williamsburg. John D. Calandra Italian American Institute, Manhattan, June 22, 2011.
  Full Moon Storytelling Night: Folk Tales and Tellers from Guyana. St. Stephen's Church, East Flatbush, June 1, 2011.
  Moonlight Stories in the Garden. Prospect Heights Community Farm, June 2, 2011.
  The Great Brooklyn Storytelling Event. Brooklyn Public Library, Grand Army Plaza, June 11, 2011.
  Stories in the Park. Lefferts Historic House, Prospect Park, June 12, 2011.
  - Sub-series 10.1: Program Files
    - Invoices and Check Requests, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
    - Funding, Corporate and Foundations, 2010 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Funding, NEA, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Publicity, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Events, Contracts and Evaluations, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Enchanted Brooklyn: Contemporary Fairy Tale Films, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Full Moon Storytelling Night, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - The Great Brooklyn Storytelling Event, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Traditional Storytellers and Their Tales, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - The Tower's Tale: Sacred Story and the Giglio Feast, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Participants, About, 2004, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Participants, Permission Statements, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Interview Logs, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Permission Statements with Interview Logs, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Research, Brooklyn Storytellers, 2009-2011 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Research, Correspondence, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Research, Organizations and Individuals, 2011 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Research, Other Projects, 2005-2012 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Research, Press Clippings, 2007-2013 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Research, Sources: Abrahams, Roger D, The Complex Relations of Simple Forms, 1981, 2009 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Research, Sources: Abrahams, Roger D, The Man of Words in the West Indies, 1983 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Research, Sources: Eder, Donna, Life Lessons Through Storytelling, 2010 (Box 72, Folder 23)
    - Research, Sources: Kirschenblatt-Gimblett, Barbara, Speech Play, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 24)
    - Research, Sources: Young, Terrell A., Happily Ever After, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 25)
    - Research, Stories, Misc., 1979 (Box 72, Folder 26)
    - Research, Women and Storytelling, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 27)
  - Sub-series 10.2: Audiovisual
    Events represented in the Audiovisual sub-series:
    - Great Brooklyn Storytelling Event, 2011 (Box 73, Item 1-11)
    - Stories in the Park, 2011 (Box 73, Item 12-14)
    - Full Moon Storytelling Night: Folk Tales and Tellers from Guyana, 2011 (Box 73, Item 15-18)
    - Moonlight Stories in the Garden, 2012 (Box 73, Item 19-23)
    - Interviews (Box 73, Item 24-26)
- Series 11: Praise in the Park: Musical Expressions of Faith
  Praise in the Park: Musical Expressions of Faith was created and produced by Kay Turner, Folk Arts Director at the Brooklyn Arts Council. Held annually from 1999-2002 at the Prospect Park Musical Pagoda, the program featured performances of traditional praise from houses of worship across Brooklyn, bringing spiritually inspired music and dance to a secular general audience. The program also included a display of devotional artifacts.
  Program files include artist information and evaluation forms, event permits, map, and production notes. Promotional materials include mailers, press releases, and brochures. Audiovisual documentation includes print photographs, recordings of events, and interviews with the 2002 participating artists. For additional materials see Box 5, folder 7.
  Praise in the Park events included:
  May 16, 1999
  Red Hawk Indian Arts Council. Powwow.
  Choir of Russian Orthodox Cathedral of the Transfiguration of Our Lord and Ensemble Eterna Muziko. Unaccompanied choral singing.
  The Word. A 19 member Big Band performing gospel songs.
  Pizmonim: Middle Eastern Music from the Jewish Sephardic Community Center.
  The Sri Ram Mandir. Kirtan and abhanga, bhajan, and chowtaal.
  Charlie Storey and His All-Stars. Arrangements of traditional folk hymns, church songs, and gospel standards.
  June 4, 2000
  Mesaouda Judeo Arabic Ensemble with Three Guest Chazzanim: David Shiro, Mark Hazan, and George Mordecai
  Sutra Dance with Song Hee Lee. Korean Buddhist music.
  Keba
  Elder Statesmen
  Charlie Storey and His All-Stars
  Los Afortunados. Afro-Cuban palo and Puerto Rican espiritismo.
  June 3, 2001
  Bahia Kao featuraing Rita Silva. Dance and drumming from Brazilian candomblé.
  Mesaouda Judeo Arabic Ensemble featuring Canton Mark Hazan. Jewish-Arabic music traditions.
  The New York State Haitian Interdenominational Mass Gospel Choir featuring Dickson Guillaume. A 50 piece gospel choir performing creolized gospel.
  New York Tan and Classical Chutney Champs featuring Dino Boodram. Indo-Caribbean tan singing.
  Song Hee Lee. Korean Buddhist music.
  September 15, 2002
  Catholic Melkite Church of the Virgin Mary Choir. Liturgical traditions in Greek, Arabic, and English.
  The Giglio Band. A ten piece processional band playing songs of the Giglio.
  Mariachi Real de Mexico, Mariachi Estrella, and Mariachi Mexico Lindo. Songs for Santa Cecilia.
  La Troupe Makandal with Frisner Augustin, Haitian Lenten rara, and Mambo Marie. Songs of praise to the Vodun Iwa.
  - Sub-series 11.1: Program Files
    - Contracts and Maps, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Production Notes, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Promotional, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Funding, NEA, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Map, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Promotional, Letters of Interest, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Artist Evaluation Form, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Artist Information, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Evaluation Form, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Maps and Event Signage, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Production Notes, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Promotional, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Special Event Permit, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Artist Research, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Contacts, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Map, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Photographs, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Production Notes, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Promotional, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Special Event Permit, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - Sub-series 11.2: Audiovisual
    Sutra Dance with Songhee Lee. Korean Buddhist music.
    Songhee Lee. Korean Buddhist music.
    Naji Yousseff, August 28, 2002
    Felix Sanabria and Susan Richardson Sanabria, August 17, 2002, two cassettes
    Barbara Giancola, August 19, 2002
    Father John Faraj, August 20, 2002
    Ramon Ponce, 2002
    - Audio, 2000 (Box 75, Item 1)
    - Audio, 2001 (Box 75, Item 2-7)
    - Audio, 2002 (Box 75, Item 8-9)
    - Video, 2002 (Box 75, Item 10)
    - Interviews, 2002 (Box 75, Item 11-16)
- Series 12: September 11th Memorial Projects
  The September 11th Memorial Projects were an annual program to commemorate the 2001 attacks on the World Trade Center while exploring and documenting various memorial traditions in Brooklyn. The project ran from 2005-2011, with a new theme introduced each year. See sub-series historical notes for details on each project.
  - Sub-series 12.1: Art of Memory/Art of Memorial
    Art of Memory/Art of Memorial was held on September 10, 2005 at the Brooklyn Historical Society. Panelists discussed the "art of memory" and the tradition of memorial monuments in Brooklyn including the Beacon Memorial (dedicated May 2005). Public Memory, a film about American memorials was shown after the discussion.
    Panelists:
    Dr. Kay Turner, BAC Folklorist
    Robert Ressler, Artist and Creator of the "Beacon" memorial
    Francis Morrone, Historian and Brooklyn architecture scholar
    Steve Seitlin, Director of City of Lore, and curator of Missing, an exhibit on 9/11
    Amy Gerber, FlatCoatFilms, LLC, Director of Public Memory
    Franchot Lee, Photographer
    This sub-series includes one folder containing promotional materials, evaluation forms, correspondence, and sign up sheets.
    - Promotional, 2005 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series 12.2: Here Was New York: Twin Towers in Memorial Images
    Here Was New York: Twin Towers in Memorial Images was a photo exhibition held in eleven Brooklyn galleries with work submitted by people from the New York area. Over 300 photographs documented the World Trade Center towers as seen in wall murals, painted trucks, graffiti, home displays, and tattoos in an effort to demonstrate forms of remembrance in a post 9/11 world. The exhibit was modeled on Here is New York, a 2001 photography exhibit that invited New Yorkers to hang images documenting September 11th.
    Galleries Included:
    BAC Gallery
    5+5 Gallery
    Safe-T Gallery
    Gloria Kennedy Gallery
    Goloborotko's Studio
    Brooklyn Historical Society
    3rd Ward
    Cinders Gallery
    City Reliquary
    Proteus Gowanus
    ElevenTen Gallery SONYA
    McCaig-Welles
    This bulk of this sub-series includes signed photographer submission forms and photographs. Also included are promotional materials, exhibit labels and plans, and calls for submissions.
    - Promotional, Oversize, 2006 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Photographer Lists, Exhibition Information, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Submission Forms Without Photographs, Labels, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Barker, Sarah, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Barros, Rita, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Becker, Michelle Aki, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Bornholtz, Steven, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Brush, Victoria, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Cherkewski, Anita, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Cherry, Michael, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - The City Reliquary, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Clarke, Alison, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Condon, Eileen, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Court, Artelia, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Devero, Annette, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - DeVito, Fred J., 2006 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Dredericks, Christiaan, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Dinshaw, Carolyn, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Dr. Drum, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Elder, Melissa, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Epes, Maria, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Fenger, Lisa, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Fossard, Etieme, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Frankel, Bruce, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - G, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Halporn, Constance H., 2006 (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Handy, Jolene Varley, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - Haney, Vanessa, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 28)
    - Hart, David, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 29)
    - Hutchinson, Sydney, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 30)
    - Hirsch, Robert, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 31)
    - Incampo, Melissa, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 32)
    - Isles, Stephani, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - Katz, Kitty, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - Krzeminska, Zofia Kamila, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 35)
    - Lane, Bettye, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 36)
    - Lee, Franchot T., 2006 (Box 76, Folder 37)
    - Long, Marget, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 38)
    - Longo, Liz and Hiram, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 39)
    - Longo, Richard F. and Liz, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 40)
    - Margolis, Paul, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 41-43)
    - Marreno, Elena, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Mason, Todd, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - McPhelim, Mary Ellen, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Ostrander, Janis, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Patous, Paul, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Picton, David, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Raczkiowicz, Justine, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Racnier, Helaine, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Ratner, Rochelle, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Reifeiss, Katrin, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Rockwell, Geoffrey, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Rodriguez, Jessica, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Ryan, B.J., 2006 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Schaefer, Robert A. Jr., 2006 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Schwartz, Molly, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Schwittek, Sara K., 2006 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Sciorra, Joe, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Sciarrino, Stefanie, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Shield, Sonja, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Smith, Mona, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Smotherman, Darby, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Sokolin, Deanne, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Something, Jonathan Wesley, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Stein, Fred, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Sterling, Carol, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Sturman, Sally Mara, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Sullivan, Kerry Ann, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Turner, Kay, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Unidentified, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Vita, Grazia, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 30)
    - Walker, John, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 31)
    - Weinberg, Louise, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 32)
    - Weiner, Hal, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Weiss, Ella, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - World Trade Center Family Center, Dr. Demaria, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Xiao, An, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Yamada, Takeshi, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Not Accepted, 2006 (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - Photographers A-H, Oversize, 2006 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Photographers I-P, Oversize, 2006 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Photographers Q-Z, Oversize (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 12.3: September 11th Remembered in Film
    September 11th Remembered in Film was a screening of documentary and interpretive films inspired by the September 11th attacks and it's aftermath, which ran from September 7-10, 2007. Discussions with the filmmakers took place after the screenings.
    Screening Schedule:
    Communities, September 7th
    American Dreams #3, Moira Tierney
    9/11 Bronx, Queens, Brooklyn, Randi Cecchine
    9/12: From Chaos to Community, Susanna Styron
    Through My Eyes, Shawn Batey
    All Our Sons: Fallen Heros of 9/11, Lillian Benson
    Parallels, September 8th
    Watching Smoke from the Otherside, Sara Ching-Yu Sun
    Market Day, Anita Glesta
    Legally Blind, Ingrid Rojas
    Demons, Tyler Cartner
    Stardust, Conlin Gee
    We Are Family, Danny Schechter
    I Heart Hip-Hop in Morocco, Josh Asen
    Windows, September 9th
    Say Can You See, Tony Caio
    Zahira's Peace, Nina Rosenblum
    Welcome to New York, Norman Cowie
    The History Makers, Louise Tiranoff/Lynn McVeigh
    America Rebuilds II- Return to Ground Zero, Kenneth Mandel/Daniel Polin
    Vigils, September 10th
    The Disappearing View, Simon Lund
    Searching for Sense, Katja Esson
    In the Spirit of Peace, Al Santana
    Parallel Lines, Nina Davenport
    FDNY Thank You Ride, Make Gaughan
    In Memoriam 9/11, Alicia Ng
    Closure, D.R. Hernandez
    The bulk of this sub-series includes copies of the films accepted and not accepted for screening. Additional items include applications, promotional materials, and notes.
    - Application and Terms, Films Used, 2007 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Application and Terms, Films Not Used, 2007 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 2007 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Schedules and Notes, 2007 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Films Used, DVD and VHS, 2007 (Box 80, Item 1-30)
    - Films Not Used, DVD and VHS, 2007 (Box 81, Item 1-10)
  - Sub-series 12.4: September 11th Memorials: Tracing the Traces of Their History
    September 11th Memorials: Tracing the Traces of Their History is an essay written by Kay Turner for the seventh anniversary of the September 11th attacks. Turner traces the legacy of the ephemeral memorials created in New York City and their relation to other expressions of mourning.
    This sub-series includes one folder with a printed copy of the essay as it appeared on the Brooklyn Arts Council website.
    - Essay, 2008 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 12.5: September 11th Memorial Sing
    Biographical Note
    Memorial Sing was a concert that took place on the evening of September 11, 2009 at the Powerhouse Arena. Performers submitted original songs about September 11th through an open call, and Folk Arts selected twenty-one to be performed. Originally planned as an outdoor event, Memorial Sing was moved to the Powerhouse Arena due to rain.
    This sub-series includes artist submission forms and audio, as well as promotional materials, permit information and a final performance list.
    Selected Song List:
    Cliff Matias, Honor Song
    Tom Chelston, Never Forget
    Annie Dinerman, Talking with Friends
    Alex Schein, Breathe Out
    Jane Byaela, This Tower's Burning
    Dave Hall, Two Cities
    Papa Dish, The September 11th Song
    Michael Hill, Heart of New York
    Bob Wright, The Dust Come Down
    Doug Katsaros, Ordinary Hero
    Eric Kivnick and Fourth Graders from PS 48, Twin Towers
    Jan Bell, No Country
    Brian DeVale, NY's Damn Bravest
    Roberta Scott, Angel Wings
    Bruce Markow, Let's Be Honest
    Bev Grant, Truth That's Real
    Colin Steel, Brooklyn Bridge
    Hilary Hawke, This Country
    Wendy Starland, Stolen Love
    Steve Wallace, Packages
    Tah Phrum De Bush, WTC
    - Artist Information, 2009 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Permit and Insurance Information, 2009 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Program, 2009 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Permissions Forms and Correspondence, 2009 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Promotional, 2009 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Press Clippings, 2009 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Submission CDs and Cassettes, 2009 (Box 82, Item 1-47)
    - Submission CDs and Cassettes, Duplicates, 2009 (Box 82, Item 48-52)
  - Sub-series 12.6: September 11th Memorial Poetry Project
    September 11th Memorial Poetry Project was a project to collect and share poems inspired by the September 11th attacks. Poets submitted their work and selections were read live at the P.S. Bookshop on September 9, 2010. The poems were also made available on the Brooklyn Arts Council website.
    This sub-series includes poetry submissions and releases, as well as a print out of the selected poems from the Brooklyn Arts Council website. Audiovisual materials include CDs with photographs and video of the live reading at P.S. Bookshop.
    Poems Read:
    Dana Leslie Goldstein, Ready or Not and On Waking (After Almost a Decade)
    Michael Cook, AFTERMATH
    Norman Stock, What I Said and New York: Save for Later
    Kyla Marshell, DEATH'S WAY
    Michael Schwartz, The Disarming
    Velez Moore, Running Man
    Tim Suermondt, MISSING SUPPER and RUBIES OF BABYLON
    Hillary Gardner, Thirteen Ways of Looking at the Aftermath
    Lawrence Swan, Jackinbox
    Juliet P. Howard, 9/11
    Jeannine Bardo, Light
    Austin Alexis, RELIC
    Melinda Thomsen, New York Blood Center
    Cynthia Hilts, Emma's Light
    - Submissions, 2010 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Releases, 2010 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Website, 2010 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Video, 2010 (Box 82, Item 53)
    - Photographs, 2010 (Box 82, Item 54-55)
  - Sub-series 12.7: Return, Remember: Ephemeral Memories in the Legacy of September 11th
    Return, Remember: Ephemeral Memorials in the Legacy of September 11th marked the ten year anniversary of the attacks and was the final September 11th Memorial Project. The 2011 program focused on ephemeral memories that were created spontaneously in New York in the weeks after the attack. Folk Arts invited people to create a simple memorial, photograph it, and submit the photos to be included on the Brooklyn Arts Council website. A panel discussion was held on September 2, 2011 at the Powerhouse Arena to assess the legacy of the memorials created after the attack. The event also included a book launch and sighing for Remembering 9/11, by photographer Martha Cooper, who was one of the panelists. The final part of the program was Rethinking Memorial: Ten Interactive Sites for Remembering 9/11, an outdoor exhibition of ten interactive memorial stations created by artists, held on September 10, 2011.
    Materials in this sub-series include calls for submission, two promotional post card, information about similar events, funding and expense information. Audiovisual materials include video records of the September 2nd panel. Ephemera items collected from the Rethinking Memorial: Ten Interactive Sites for Remembering 9/11 exhibit are also included.
    Martha Cooper, documentary photographer
    Steve Zeitlin, Director of City Love
    Kay Turner, Folk Arts Director, Brooklyn Arts Council
    Lisa Radakovich Holsberg, Long Island University, C.W. Post
    Marci Reaven, Vice President for History Exhibitions, Brooklyn Historical Society
    Bob Holman, Poet
    Harriet F. Senie, Director of Museum Studies and Professor of Art History, City College
    Rethinking Memorial: Ten Interactive Sites for Remembering 9/11 Artists:
    Kimberly Carmody
    Matt Freedman
    Kay Turner
    Jennifer Cecere
    Michael McDevitt
    Friendly Falcons
    Legacy Russell
    Sonya Belofsky
    Dylan Angell
    - Event Planning and Signage, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Promotional, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Calls for Submissions, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Related Events, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Expenses, Check Requests, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Expenses, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - Funding, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - Panel Video, CD and Cassettes, 2011 (Box 82, Item 56-58)
    - Ephemera (Box 83)
    - Ephemera (Box 84)